以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
谈论梯度下降和和
talk about gradient descent and the and
它的后代也是基本的
its descendants so from the basic
我们所有的梯度下降公式
gradient descent formula which we all
知道让我写下来的新
know let me just write that down the new
要点是我们要走的旧点
point is the old point we're going
向下，所以用减号表示
downwards so with a minus sign that's
步长我们计算
the step size and we compute the
在XK的梯度，所以我们正在下降
gradient at X K so we're descending in
负梯度的方向
the direction of the negative gradient
这是基本的公式，并在
and that's the basic formula and is in
每本书都是我研究的主要参考书
every book studied so my main reference
对于这些讲座中的一些是
for the some of these lectures is the
斯蒂芬博伊德和林登的书
book by Stephen Boyd and Linden and
范登堡和我再次提到
Vandenberg and and I mentioned again
博伊德教授在这个房间里说话
professor Boyd is talking in this room
下周三周三和周四
next week Wednesday Thursday and and
他周五在某个地方说话
he's speaking somewhere on Friday at
4:30当然还有优化
4:30 and of course about optimization
他是个好讲师，非常好
and he's a good lecturer yeah very good
好的，所以有最陡的下降和
okay so there's steepest descent and
我上次重绘了我的照片
I've redrawn my picture from last time
我会去那边看看那个
that I'll go over there and look at that
图片，但让我说出来的是什么
picture but let me say what's coming so
这是非常标准非常标准的你
that's pretty standard very standard you
可以说这是改善
could say then this is the improvement
被广泛使用添加的东西
that is widely used adding in something
称为动量以避免之字形
called momentum to avoid the zigzag that
我们要去看看
we're going to see
还有另一种方法可以做到这一点
and there's another way to do it there's
一个名叫内斯特的俄罗斯人
a Russian guy named Nestor off his
论文不容易阅读，但他们已经
papers are not easy to read but they've
得到了严肃的内容，他做了一件事
got serious content and one thing he did
被找到的势头替代方案，
was find an alternative to momentum that
也加速了下降所以这
also accelerated the the descent so this
产生这两者产生更快
produces these both produce faster
血统比普通的一个好和
descent than the ordinary one okay and
然后你知道展望未来
then you know looking ahead that for
机器学习的问题就是这样
problems of machine learning they're so
大的梯度，我们有这么
large that the gradient and we have so
许多变量都是那些权重
many variables all those weights are
变量全部和那可能数百个
variables all and that could hundreds of
成千上万并不罕见
thousands is is not uncommon
这样梯度就变成了
so that then the gradient becomes a
相当大的计算，我们没有
pretty big calculation and we don't have
做这一切的，一旦我们不必
to do it all at once we don't have to
改变所以xk是所有的向量
change so xk is a vector of all the
权重或使用和我们的方程
weights or and using and our equations
是匹配训练数据
are the matching the the training data
所以我们不必使用所有的培训
so we don't have to use all the training
数据一下子我们不接受
data at once and we don't we take a
一批训练数据，但一个
batch of training data like one but
这种方式效率低下
that's sort of inefficient in the
相反的方向，他们做一个在一个
opposite direction they do them one at a
时间，所以我们不想与他们做
time so we don't want to do with them
一次一个，但我们不想这样做
one at a time but we don't want to do
一次只有百万
all all million at a time
因此妥协是一个小批量
so the compromise is a mini batch so
讽刺的渐变血统做迷你
sarcastic gradient descent does a mini
批量一次一个小批次的
batch at a time a mini batch of of
每个样本培训数据的培训
training of samples training data each
步骤，它可以选择它们
step and it can choose them
随机地或随机地意义
stochastically meaning randomly or
坐得更系统，但我们做了一个
sitting more systematically but we do a
一批在时间和会后
batch at a time and that will come after
该
the
它将在下周马拉松比赛后出现
it'll come next week after a marathon of
当然星期一好吧让我走吧
course on Monday okay so let me just go
回到那张照片片刻，但是
back to that picture for a moment but
那么今天真正的内容就是这个
then the real content of today is this
一个动量增加好吧，我只是我
one with momentum added okay I just I
可能没有完美的画面
probably haven't got the picture perfect
但我认为我不是艺术家
yet I'm just not an artist but I think
我离我很近，所以这就是那些
I'm closer so this is uh those are the
级别设置那些是X的集合f
level sets those are the sets f of X
等于常数和我们的模型问题
equal constant and in our model problem
X的f是X1平方或者说x
f of X is X 1 squared or let's say x
平方加上By平方等于常数
squared plus B y squared equal constants
小B低于1，可能远
with small B be below 1 and maybe far
低于1所以那些是椭圆形的那些
below 1 so those are ellipses those the
椭圆的方程式，这就是什么
equations of an ellipse and that's what
我试图绘制，如果B小则那么
I tried to draw and if B is small then
椭圆形长而薄
the ellipses are long and thin like that
现在你的照片是什么样的
and now what's what's the picture you
从一点开始，没有你和你
start with a point X naught and you
以最陡的方向下降所以
descend in the steepest direction so the
最陡的方向垂直于
steepest direction is perpendicular to
水平设置正确垂直于
the level set right perpendicular to the
椭圆让你倒下来
ellipse so you down down down you're
更多地通过更多的椭圆
passing through more ellipses more
省略号更多省略号最终你的
ellipses more ellipses eventually your
切线在我看来，它必须是
tangent to it seems to me it has to be
切线我没看过这个，但它看起来
tangent I didn't read this but it looks
对我来说合理的是最远的
reasonable to me that the the farthest
在水平设置最远的椭圆形你是
in level-set farthest an ellipse you're
相切，然后你开始上升
tangent to and then you start going up
再次，这是最佳点
again so that's the optimal point to
停止结束那一步，然后在哪里
stop to end that step and then where
下一步是否顺利，你就在这里
does the next step go well you're here
你在一个水平集的椭圆上
you're on an ellipse that's a level set
你想要在渐变中移动
you want to move in the gradient
与...垂直的方向
direction that's perpendicular to the
水平设置，所以你要去某个地方
level set so you're going down somewhere
在这里，你又过去了
here and you're passing again through
越来越多的椭圆直到你的
more and more ellipses until your
与...相切
tangent to a
在这里和你一个较小的椭圆
to a smaller ellipse here and and you
看到之字形图案和锯齿形
see the zig-zag pattern and that zig-zag
模式是我们通过公式看到的
pattern is what we see by formula in in
博伊德的书和许多其他地方也是如此
Boyd's book and many other places too
公式有权力
the formula has the there was powers of
一个神奇数字的光束，所以我们开始
a beam of the magic number so we start
在点b1开始并按照这个
at start at the point b1 and follow this
路径然后X是相同的B次
path then the X's are the same B times
这个数量与案件的权力和
this quantity to the case power and
这是B的数量减去1
here's that quantity B minus 1 over B
加1，所以你看到一个小B的
plus 1 so you see for a small B that's
这是一个负数，所以它是
that's a negative number so it's
翻转迹象在X的，因为我们看到了
flipping sign in the X's as we saw on
图片
the pictures
留下那部分图片
leave that part of the picture is
纠正Y的不要翻转标志所以这个
correct the Y's don't flip sign so this
是XK，当K为0时我们得到BYK就是我
was XK and when K is 0 we got B YK is I
认为这是没有翻转的迹象，使
think is is not flipping a sign so that
看起来的F好，然后FK值
looks good and then FK the value of F
也是相同的数量
also was the same quantity
FK与案件的数量相同
FK is that same quantity to the case
次f0
times f0
所以数量就是最重要的
so that quantity is all all-important
所以今天演讲的目的是
and so the purpose of today's lecture is
告诉你什么动力术语是什么
to tell you what the momentum term what
改善带来的变化
improvement what change that brings in
我最基本的最陡下降公式
the basic steepest descent formula I'm
要加上另一个正在进行的术语
gonna add on another term which is going
有一些给我们一些记忆
to have some give us some memory of the
前面的步骤，所以当我这样做
previous step and so when I do that
我想追踪那种下降
I want to track that kind of descent for
对于新的加速下降
for the new for the accelerated descent
并跟踪它，看看有什么改进
and track it and see what improvement
动量术语带来了所以
the momentum term brings and so the
最后的结果将告诉你
final result will be to tell you the
改进了产品
improvement in the produce by the
动量术语也许我有你的时候
momentum term maybe while I have your
注意我会告诉你它现在是什么
attention I'll tell you what it is now
然后我们将详细介绍
and then we'll come the details the
代数和我，所以这是我自己的
algebra and to me so this is my own
认为这是代数的奇迹
thought it's a miracle that the algebra
你真的看到这很简单
which is straightforward you really see
特征向量的值
the value of eigenvectors
你知道我们解释了特征向量
you know we explain eigenvectors in
上课，但在这里，你明白为什么如何
class but but here you see why what how
使用它们这的确是一个不错
to use them that's is really a good
但对我而言，这是一个奇迹
exercise but to me it's a miracle that
动量的表达非常
the expression with momentum is very
很像那种表达，但不同
much like that expression but different
当然腐烂是一个术语
of course the the the decay is a term
它告诉你腐烂的速度有多快
that tells you how fast the decay is is
更小，所以你就是这样服用K的力量
smaller so you're taking K power so so
如果那样的话，让我写下来
let me I'll write that down if that's
好吧这是我不打算做
all right it's I didn't plan to do to
在开始时揭示最终结果
reveal the final result at the beginning
讲座的，但我想你想
of the lecture but I think you want to
看看我们在哪里这么做
see where we're going so so with
势头，我们必须看到这一点
momentum and we have to see what that
意味着这个术语1减去B超过1
means this this term of 1 minus B over 1
加B变为
plus B becomes changes to
一个减去B的平方根超过1加
one minus square root of B over 1 plus
广场就这样我提到了
square would be so I mentioned that
之前，但我不认为我写了它
before but but I don't think I wrote it
只是清楚地说明这对我来说是个奇迹
down just clearly so the miracle to me
是为了获得这样一个很好的表达
is to get such a nice expression for the
因为你会看到代数就是它
because you'll see the algebra is it
有效，但它涉及更多
works but it's it's it involves more
因动量而涉及的条款
terms because of momentum involves doing
最小化特征值然而它
a minimization of eigenvalues and yet it
出来很好，然后你有
comes out nicely and and then you have
看到它的重要性所以让我
to see the importance of that so let me
我只想采用相同的例子
I would just take the same example that
如果B超过100，我之前提到过
I mentioned before if B is 1 over 100
那么这是0.99超过1.01哦我想
then this is 0.99 over 1.01 oh I think
这些在这里有一个正方形2K所以
that these there's a square here 2 K so
如果我们这样的话，我会保留这个
if we're so I'll I'll just keep this
广场上没有什么大变化，但我是
square there no big change but but I'm
现在看着广场
looking at now here at the square
也许广场到处都是你
maybe maybe squares are everywhere you
知道好，所以接近1现在
know ok so so that's close to 1 and now
让我们比较的是什么，我们有这么
let's compare that with what we have so
如果b为1超过100，所以我服用V至是
if B is 1 over 100 so I'm taking V to be
1超过100然后B的平方根是1
1 over 100 then square root of B is 1
超过10所以这是0.9比0.9超过1.1
over 10 so this is 0.9 0.9 over 1.1
平方，这是一个巨大的嗯
squared and there's a tremendous um
比这更小的块是正确的
block smaller than that is right
9/1099/11与99比99
9/10 9 9 / 11 compared to 99 over 101
这一个你知道的绝对是哦
this one is you know is definitely oh
对不起，是的，就是这个减少
sorry it's yeah it's this this reduction
因素远低于那个，所以它是一个
factor is well below that one so it's a
值得做的好事，没关系
good thing it's worth doing and okay
现在它涉及什么，好吧，所以我会
now what is it involved okay so I'll
写下for的表达式
write down the expression for the for
讽刺在这里我们没事
the sarcastic here we go okay
所以这是一种看待新X的方法
so here's one way to see it the new X is
旧X减去渐变现在
the old X minus the gradient and now
是一个额外的术语，它给了我们一个
comes an extra term which gives us a
很少记忆我很抱歉
little memory well I'm sorry the the
如果我写代数，代数会稍微好一些
algebra is slightly nicer if I write it
有点不同我会创建一个
a little bit differently I'll create a
新的数量ZK步长可以
new quantity ZK with a step size okay
好吧，如果我把ZK当成了
okay so if I took ZK to be just the
梯度最陡的下降
gradient that would be steepest descent
一切都没有改变，而是我
nothing has changed but instead I'm
要把ZK带到其领先的术语意志
gonna take ZK well its leading term will
是渐变但是来了
be the gradient but here comes the
动量术语我添加了多个beta
momentum term I add on a multiple beta
一种方法是先前Z所以
one way to do it is of the previous Z so
Z是搜索方向z是
the Z is the search direction z is the
渐变你正在旅行它是
gradient you're traveling it's the
方向你移动所以它是
direction you're moving so it's
从该方向有不同的
different from that direction there that
方向是这个梯度
direction was the gradient this
方向是渐变正确的
direction is the gradient correct
用记忆词来纠正动量
corrected by a memory term a momentum
术语和解释的一种方式是
term and one way to interpret that is to
说那个球是想到的
say that that ball is to think of a
沉重的球而不仅仅是一点我
heavy ball instead of just a point I
想到一个沉重的球而不是
think of a heavy ball it instead of
像来一样来回蹦蹦跳跳
bouncing back and forth as as as as
它倾向于无用
uselessly as this one it tends to
当然它仍然在两侧反弹
it still bounces of course on the sides
水平集但它下来了
of the level sets but it comes down the
谷更快，这就是效果
valley faster and that's the effect of
这样所以你可以玩不同的
this so so you could play with different
调整术语不同的更正
adjustment terms different Corrections
所以，但我会完成这一个
so but I'll follow through this one
Nesterov还有另一种方法可以做到
Nesterov had another way to make a
改变公式和有
change in the formula and the there are
当然其他人还可以
certainly others beyond that okay
那么，我们如何分析一个很好
so how do we analyze that one well
他们真正的重点是我们有点
they're the real point is we've sort of
通过涉及前一步骤
by taking by involving the previous step
我们现在有一个三级方法
we now have a three level method instead
你可以说两级方法
of a two level method you could say
这就是这只涉及k级
there's this this involves only level k
现在加1和K级公式
plus 1 and level K the formulas now
涉及k加1k和k减1
involve k plus 1 k and k minus 1 it's
就像从第一顺序出发一样
just like going from a first-order
微分方程到二阶
differential equation to a second-order
微分方程
differential equation
是的，我不是真的在想K
it's it's I'm not really thinking that K
是一个时间变量，但在
is a is a time variable but in the
类比K可以是时间变量
analogy K could be a time variable so
在这里，我们喜欢一阶
that here we had like a first-order
等式，如果我想模拟那个
equation if I wanted to model that
那是一种DXDT进入那里
that's sort of a DX DT coming in there
等于梯度和这些模型
equal a gradient and and these models
非常有用，并为之开发
are highly useful and and developed for
一种连续的最陡峭的模型
sort of a continuous model of steepest
下降连续运动而不是
descent a continuous motion instead of
的，而不是离散的运动行
the instead of the discrete motion okay
那就是那个连续的模型
so that would that's continuous model
因为那个人将是第一个订单
for that guy would be a first order in
这一次的时间将是二阶
time for this one it'll be second order
时间和二阶方程
in time and second order equations of
当然和是常数系数
course and the be constant coefficients
在我们的模型问题和关于
in our model problem and the thing about
我们都知道的二阶方程
a second-order equation that we all know
有一个动量项是一个阻尼项
there's a momentum term a a damping term
你可以说乘以第一个
you could say in multiplying the first
衍生所以这就是什么
derivative so that's what that's what a
二阶方程提供的是
second-order equation offers is the
包含阻尼项而不是
inclusion of a damping term which isn't
存在于原文中
present in the in the original
一阶还好，我们如何分析
first-order okay so how do we analyze
我必须这样你怎么分析
this I have to so how do you analyze
你的二阶微分方程
second-order differential equations you
首先将它们写成两个系统
write them as a system of two first
订购方程式正是如此
order equations so that's exactly what
我们将在离散的地方做这里
we're going to do here in the discrete
我们当然会看到我们的情况
case we're going to see of course we
有两个方程式和它们的第一个顺序
have two equations and their first order
而且我们可以让我和他们一起玩
and and we can let me play with them for
几分钟的时间来让他们很好的好了，
a moment to to make them good okay so
我会这样，这将是2
I'm gonna have so this will go to 2
第一阶方程，其中第一
first order equations in which the first
一个我要复制XK加1是XK
one I'm just gonna copy XK plus 1 is XK
减去步长ZK哇哇呀，是的
minus at step size ZK whew yeah ok yeah
好的时间以前的时间在这里输入
ok time the previous times type here the
左边的下一步好吧，所以我
the next time step on the left okay so I
刚刚复制了那个我要去的那个
just copied that now this one I'm going
如此才能有提高K内由1
to increase K by 1 so in order to have
我希望写下来
that looking to match this I'll write
因为ZK加1而我将带来
that as Z K plus 1 and I'll bring the
case不是gradFk加1等于betaZK
case ain't grad F k plus 1 equal beta ZK
看着你，我就在这里
that look with you I just in this in
这件事而不是看着它
this thing instead of looking at it at
我去K加1，我把K
ki I went to K plus 1 and I put the K
一边加1个条款好吧现在我
plus 1 terms on one side okay so now I
有一个
have a a
让我们看看让我们记住我们正在做的事情
and let's see let's remember we're doing
我们正在做的模型是f等于
our the model we're doing is f equal up
1/2X转置sX所以F的梯度
1/2 X transpose s X so the gradient of F
是X，所以我写在那里或
is s X so what I've written there or
渐变真的我知道那是什么
gradient is really I know what that
渐变是真的sxkplus
gradient is so that's really s xk plus
好吧好的，如何分析那是什么
okay okay how to analyze that what
以K为K，K前进一个
happens as K as K travels forward one
我们有两个三四五个常数
two three four five we have a constant
XZ的每一步系数问题
coefficient problem at every step the XZ
变量乘以a
variable is getting multiplied by a
矩阵所以这里的XZ在k加1和
matrix so here's X Z at k plus 1 and
在这里将是XZ在步骤K和我
over here will be X Z at step K and I
只是要搞清楚矩阵是什么
just have to figure out what matrix is
乘以这里和这里好吧，我
multiplying here and here okay and I
在这里猜测我是第一个看到的
guess here I see it if the first
等式具有1和减去s的外观
equation has a 1 and a minus s looks
就像在第一行，它有一个beta
like in the first row and it has a beta
在第二行，这里是第一行
in the second row and here the first
等式在该行中有10然后
equation has a 1 0 in that row and then
减去s我会输入减号
a minus s I'll put in minus s
将XK加1再乘以1
multiplying XK plus 1 and then the one
那个乘以ZK加1就是全部
that multiplies ZK plus 1 is that all
对
right
对不起，我有2个SS而且我没画画
sorry I've got 2 SS and I didn't draw
那个人没有写那个大的
that one didn't write that one in large
够了，无论如何我打算擦掉它
enough and I'd plan to erase it anyway
这是这个步长
this is the this is the step size this
这是矩阵，但事实并非如此
this is the matrix but but it's it's not
放置它不太合适
it's not quite fitting it's placed this
是我要使用本征的点
is the point where I'm gonna use eigen
价值观我会跟着我跟随每一个
values I'm gonna follow an I follow each
特征值是整点时的
eigen value that's the whole point when
我遵循每个特征值
I follow each eigen value
每个特征向量我应该说我会
each eigenvector I should say I'll
按照s的每个特征向量，让我们
follow each eigenvector of s so let's
让我们这样做，这样我就可以了
let's do that so so I can vectors of s
我们怎么称呼那些lambda
what are we gonna call those lambda
可能是这样的X等于lambdaXI思考
probably so s X equal lambda X I think
这就是即将到来或QI做的事情
that's what's coming or Q I to do things
我想要记住，s是一个
right I want to remember that s is a
正定对称矩阵
positive definite symmetric matrix
这就是为什么我称它为s而不是它
that's why I called it s instead of a so
我真的应该称之为本征
I really should call the eigen it
无所谓但是要在球上让
doesn't matter but to be on the ball let
我称本征向量Q和本征
me call the eigen vector Q and the eigen
价值lambda没关系，所以现在我想
value lambda okay okay so now I want to
我想跟随这个特征向量
I want to follow this eigen vector so
我假设XK是CK的一些时间
I'm supposing that X K is some C K times
问：我假设X在跟踪中
Q I'm assuming that X is in the tracking
这个特征向量，我会假设
this eigen vector and I'm gonna assume
ZK是其他一些不变的时间Q.
that ZK is some other constant times Q
大家，你看到那是一个矢量和
everybody do you see that's a vector and
这是一个向量，我想要标量我
that's a vector and I want scalars I
想要吸引标量CK和DK
want to attract just scalar C K and D K
所以我真的在这里
so that's really what I have here is
这有点棘手，因为X在这里
this was a little tricky because X here
是一个向量，两个组件是n
is a vector and two components are n
组件我不想要我真的
components I didn't want that I really
只想跟踪一个特征向量
wanted just to track an eigen vector
一旦我确定了方向Q.
once I've settled on the direction Q
一切的一切都是向量都在
everything is all vectors are in the
Q的方向所以我们就这样了
direction of Q so so we just have
数字看到确实是一条轨道好，所以我
numbers see indeed a track okay so I'm
要改写这个
gonna rewrite this
正确，因为是的，让我继续保持
correctly as yeah well let me keep keep
按照这个小公式去做什么
going with this little formula then what
我需要一个SX将会是什么样的
will I needed an SX what will s xk be if
如果xk在特征方向上
if xk is in the direction of the eigen
矢量Q及其CK当我发生时会发生什么
vector Q and its CK what happens when I
乘以是q是一个特征向量
multiply by yes q was an eigen vector so
乘以s给了我可以
the multiplying by s gives me I can
价值正确所以它是CKlambdaQ.
value right so it's C K lambda Q
一切都是Q的倍数而且是
everything is a multiple of Q and it's
只有那些我正在寻找的倍数
only those multiples I'm looking for the
海和DS然后是lambda
Seas and the DS and then the lambda
进入S期间，我想是的
comes into the S term yeah I think
这可能是我需要做到这一点
that's probably all I need to to do this
然后渐变是啊所以这是
and then the gradient yeah so that's the
渐变当然这是渐变
gradient of course this is the gradient
的F好了，取而代之的是让我
of F okay so instead of this let me just
写下发生了什么，如果我是
write what's what's happening if I'm
跟踪系数CK加1和
tracking the coefficients CK plus 1 and
DK加1然后我真正的意思
DK plus 1 then what I really meant to
有10和减去s是减号
have there is 1 0 and minus s is a minus
lambda是对的，当我
lambda is that right yeah when I
将特征向量乘以s我只是
multiply the eigenvector by s I'm just
开玩笑哦，它是CK的一倍
kidding oh it's a lambda times the CK
是的lambda倍于CK，这对我来说很好
yeah lambda times the CK that's good I
认为那是左手边的
think that that's the left-hand side of
我的等式，在右边我
my equation and on the right hand side I
在这里是1，这是
have here that's 1 and this was the
标量步长，这是
scalar the step size and this was the
其他系数是SNbeta所以我
other coefficient it's the SN beta so I
我想选择现在的目的
want to choose what's my purpose now
这给了我
that gives me the
在C和C的每一步都会发生什么
what happens at every step to the C and
D所以我想选择土地了
D so I want to choose the land the the
我有两件事我可以随意
two things that I have I'm free to
选择我们的s和beta，这是我的大事
choose our s and beta so that's my big
大工作选择s和beta现在我好
big job choose s and beta okay now I to
让哦让我塑造这个事情了
make oh let me just shape this thing up
按月乘以倒数
by month by multiplying the inverse of
这一点，把它在这里，这样很好
that and get it over here so that well
真的，你会看到一切所以CK加
really you'll see everything so CK plus
一个DK加一个什么是倒数
one DK plus one what's the inverse of
一零
one zero
哦，我不认为我想要那样
oh I don't think I wanna that would have
一个艰难的时期找到一个逆转它是一个
a tough time finding an inverse it was a
一个不是它是的好，所以我想
one wasn't it yeah okay so I want to
乘以该矩阵的倒数
multiply by the inverse of that matrix
在这里得到它，是什么
to get it over here and what's the
倒数11减去lamda它是1加1
inverse of 1 1 minus lamda it's 1 1 plus
lambda使逆转带来了它
lambda so that the inverse brought it
在这里时间这个矩阵10beta和
over here times this matrix 1 0 beta and
减去步长是什么的
minus the step size that's what
倍增CKDK所以我们有这些
multiplies C KD K so we have these
简单漂亮的步骤来了
simple beautiful steps which which come
从跟踪一个特征向量得到
from tracking one eigenvector makes the
整个问题标量，所以我乘以那些
whole problem scalar so I multiply those
在我们的两个矩阵中我终于得到了
two matrices in our I finally get the
矩阵，我真的要想一想
matrix that I really have to think about
10倍，即1减去slambda1
1 0 times that'll be 1 minus s lambda 1
在那里将成为一个lambda的时代
times that will be a lambda there and
减去lambdas加betabeta减去
minus lambda s plus beta beta minus
lambda是我们看到的矩阵
lambda s that's the matrix that we see
在每一步让我称之为矩阵哦
at every step let me call that matrix Oh
所以我比我做了更多的代数
so I've done some algebra more than I
总是会在演讲中做，但事实如此
would always do in a lecture but it's
真的，如果不是，我就不会这样做
really my I wouldn't do it if it wasn't
好的代数是什么结论了
nice algebra what's the conclusion the
结论是有了动力
conclusion is that with the momentum
这个数字beta的术语可用于
term with this number beta available to
选择以及S中的步骤
choose as well as s the step the
特征值的系数
coefficient of the eigenvalue
特征向量在每一步都相乘
eigenvector is multiplied at every step
通过该矩阵rr是那个矩阵和
by that matrix r r is that matrix and of
当然矩阵涉及到
course that matrix involves the
特征值是的，所以我们要考虑一下
eigenvalue yep so we have to think about
我们现在想要做什么
what what do we want to do now we want
选择beta和s来制作我们的
to choose beta and s to make our as
小编为大家想使可能的权
small as possible right we want to make
我们尽可能小，我们是自由的
our as small as possible and we're free
选择beta和s但我们只是我们的
to choose beta and s but we but our
取决于lambda所以我要做
depends on lambda so I'm going to make
它尽可能小，在整个
it as small as possible over the whole
范围可能的lambdas所以让我
range of possible lambdas so so let me
所以现在我们真的去了
so now here we really go so we have
一些这些之间的lambda是这些
lambda between some these are these are
s的本征特征值和我们的特征值
the eigen eigen value of s and what we
知道什么是合理的知道
know what's what's reasonable to know is
下限这是一个积极的，这是一个
a lower bound it's a positive this is a
对称正定矩阵
symmetric positive definite matrix a
下界和上界
lower bound and an upper bound for
例如，M是B，M是其中之一
example and M was B and M was one in
那个二乘二的问题就是这个
that two-by-two problem and this is what
我们知道特征值是
we know that the eigen values are
M＆M之间的比例
between M&M and the ratio of
M2M很好，如果我不买对的，这是这个
m2m well if I buy right this is the this
是关键数量，它是什么叫它
is the key quantity and what's it called
lambdamax除以lambdamin是
lambda max divided by lambda min is the
条件号码这就是全部
condition number right this is all
有时写Kappa希腊字母
sometimes written Kappa Greek letter
Kappa的条件数和时间
Kappa the condition number of s and when
这个问题很重要
that's big that then the problem is
将是困难时，这是一个
going to be harder when that's one that
然后矩阵只是一个倍数
then the matrix is just a multiple of
单位矩阵和所述问题是
the identity matrix and the problem is
当这个时候资本何时何时琐碎
trivial when this when when when capital
在它m和小米相同，则
in it m and small m are the same then
这是说，规模最大，
that's saying that the largest and
最小的特征值是相同的
smallest eigen values are identical that
该矩阵是的倍数
that the matrix is a multiple of the
这是条件第一的身份
identity that's the condition number one
但是糟糕的是当它结束时
but but the bad one is when it's 1 over
B在我们的例子中，它可以
B in our example and it and that could
非常大可以，这就是我们所拥有的
be very large okay that's where we have
一个问题让我只是插入一下
a problem let me just insert about the
普通的梯度下降当然了
ordinary gradient descent of course the
教科书找到了有多快的估计
textbooks find a estimate for how fast
那当然是取决于那个
that is and of course it depends on that
数
number
是啊所以它依赖于数量和E
yeah so it depends on that number and E
对，你确切地看到它是如何依赖的
right you exactly saw how it depended on
这个号码没错，但现在我们有了
that number right but now we have a
不同的问题，我们要完成
different problem and we're gonna finish
没关系，那我的工作是什么呢？
it okay so what's my job I'm gonna
选择s和beta来保持
choose s and beta to get to keep the the
R的本征值让我们给出
eigen values of R so let's give the
RNA的本征值所以R让我们说R有
eigen values of RNA so R let's say R has
特征值
eigen values
我赢得了取决于lambda和
II won that depends on on the lambda and
s和beta以及E-所以那些是
the s and the beta and E - so those are
我们刚才给出的特征值
the eigenvalues of our just giving a
给他们的信，那么我们的工作是什么
letter to to them so what's our job we
想要选择s和beta来制作它们
want to choose s and beta to make those
特征值尽可能小
eigenvalues as small as possible right
如果r小，则小的特征值
small eigenvalues if r has small
特征值它的力量看到我们每一个
eigenvalues its powers see we ever every
步骤乘以r使收敛
step multiplies by r so the convergence
动量率依赖于
rate with momentum is depends on the
我们快速变小的力量吧
powers of our getting small fast it
取决于特征值很小
depends on the eigenvalues being small
我们希望尽量减少最大的
we want to minimize the largest
特征值所以我会说e的最大值
eigenvalue so I'll say the maximum of e
1和每个和E2这是我们的工作
1 and each and E 2 that's our job
最小化我们想要选择s和beta
minimize we want to choose s and beta to
最小化最大特征值因为
minimize the largest eigenvalue because
如果有一个小的特征值，但是
if there's one small eigenvalue but the
另一个很大，另一个很重要
other is big then the other one is going
杀了我们所以我们必须得到两者
to kill us so we have to get both
特征值下降，当然还有那些
eigenvalues down and of course those
取决于lambdae1取决于lambda
depend on lambda e 1 depends on lambda
所以我们有一点代数问题
so we have a little algebra problem and
这就是我所描述的奇迹
this is what I described as a miracle
这个小代数的事实
the fact that this little algebra
问题是该矩阵的特征值
problem the eigenvalues of that matrix
e1和e2在某些方面取决于lambda
e1 and e2 which depend on lambda in some
在某种程度上，我们想要制作两个e1
in some way and we want to make both e1
和e2最小的那些
and e2 small the maximum of those of
他们，我们必须为所有人做
them and we have to do it for all the
特征所有特征值lambda因为
eigen all the eigenvalues lambda because
我们现在必须认为我们一直都是
we have to we're now thinking we've been
跟踪每个特征向量，以便给出
tracking each eigenvector so that gave
我们1所以这是所有可能的lambda
us 1 so this is for all possible lambda
哦，所以我们必须决定我的意思
oh so we have to decide what do I mean
所有意大利面
by all pasta
lambda和我的意思是所有的lambda
lambda and I mean all lambda that are
在一些M＆M之间有一个美丽的
between some M&M there is a beautiful
你有一个二乘二矩阵的问题
problem you have a two-by-two matrix you
可以找到它找到它的特征值的
can find it it find its eigenvalues its
它依赖于lambda和我们所有人
it they depend on lambda and what we all
我们所知道的λ是它的M之间
we know about lambda is it's between m
并与capya也是他们也依赖
and and capya and also they also depend
在s和beta上我们可以使用两个参数
on s and beta the two parameters we can
选择，我们想选择那些
choose and we want to choose those
参数使所有的所有
parameters so that for for all the all
可能的特征值越大
the possible eigenvalues the larger of
两个特征值将小到
the two eigenvalues will be as small as
可能这就是它的一点点
possible that's it's a little bit of
代数但你知道那是那个吗？
algebra but it's do you see that that's
我不应该说狡猾的棘手
the tricky that I shouldn't say tricky
因为它出来就是这个
because it comes out that's that this is
一来就是一个奇迹中
the one that is a miracle in the in the
简单的解决方案好吧，我
simplicity of the solution okay and I'm
会影响也许我会搬到这里
gonna effect maybe I'll move over here
把答案写好，我只是想要
to write the answer okay and I just want
说奇迹不会发生
to say that miracles don't happen so
通常在数学中，你知道所有的
often in math there's you know all of
数学的全部要点是数学
mathematics the whole point of math is
解释奇迹所以有一个
to explain miracles so there is a
这里有一些东西要解释我
there's something to explain here and I
没有我的手指上还因
don't have my finger on it yet because
无论如何它发生了让我告诉你
anyway it happens so let me tell you
什么是正确的和正确的beta和
what the right s and the right beta and
得到的最小特征值是这样的
the resulting minimum eigen value are so
他们又依赖于小米和大米
again they depend on little m and Big M
这是我们非常好的功能
that's a very nice feature which we
预计，这是他们依赖
expect and that is and they depend on
这个比例没关系，所以这个比例还好
the ratio okay so that ratio alright
让我们看看它没关系，所以最好的
let's let's see it okay so the best s
S最优具有公式二
the S optimal has the formula two over
lambdamax的平方根就是
square root of lambda max that's the
M的平方根和平方根
square root of M and the square root of
MSquared令人惊叹的好和beta最佳
M Squared amazing okay and beta optimal
原来是M的平方根
turns out to be the square root of M
减去小米的平方根
minus the square root of little m over
MPLUS平方的平方根
the square root of M plus the square
所有平方的小M的根
root of little M all the squared of
当然我们知道这些数字是1
course we know what these numbers are 1
和我们的模型问题中的beta
and beta in our model problem that's
在哪里我会得到这个平方根
where I'm gonna get this square root of
这是1减去广场对不起B这个
this is 1 minus the square sorry B this
实际上是1减去B的平方根
is 1 minus the square root of B in fact
雅为我们的例子好吧让我
ya for our for our example well let me
只要写出2比1的内容
just write what they would be 2 over 1
乙广场和1个减去加平方根
plus square root of B Square and 1 minus
将超过1加方你看
would be over 1 plus square you see
这是1减去B的平方根
where this is 1 minus square root of B
作为一个开始出现现在它出现
as a beginning to appear now it appears
在解决这个问题然后
in the solution of this problem and then
我得告诉你怎么回事
I have to tell you what the what how
小确实做了这些这些最佳选择
small did do these these optimal choices
让我们的这项权利的特征值
make the eigenvalues of our right this
是我们真正关注的
is what we're really paying attention to
因为它的特征值是该
because it's the eigen values that that
矩阵告诉我们每个人都会发生什么
matrix tells us what happens at every
步骤及其特征值必须是
step and the its eigen values have to be
如何获得快速收敛
small to get fast convergence so how
他们很好，他们涉及这个
small are they well they involve this
是的，这是我见过的数字
yeah so it's the number that I've seen
所以在这种情况下轻松了
so so in this case the ease the
特征值
eigenvalues
我们那是迭代矩阵
of our that's the iterating matrix are
现在我们现在你要去了
below that now we're now you're gonna
看到一个-都将超过1加
see that one - were to be over 1 plus
我们认为也许平方让我
we're to be I think maybe squared let me
只是看是的是的它恰好来了
just see yeah yeah it happens to come
再次出这个数字，这就是
out that number again so that's the
结论是正确的选择
conclusion that was the right choice of
s和beta通过添加这个回顾期限
s and beta by adding this look-back term
回头一步，你得到这个
look back one step you get this
改善，这是你看到的
improvement and it's it happens you see
它在实践当然你会看到它
it in practice of course you'll see it
确切地说，你完成了这项工作
exactly and so you you do the job to use
现在的势头我会提到什么
momentum now I'm going to mention what
NesterovNesterov有一点点
the Nesterov Nesterov had a slightly
不同的方式去做，我会告诉你
different way to do it and i'll tell you
这是什么，但它是相同的想法得到
what that is but it's the same idea get
第二件事让我们看看能不能
a second thing so let's see if I can
发现是的nestor哦，好的，我们在这里
find that yeah nestor oh ok ok here we
走
go
所以让我给内斯特打下个名字
so let me bring Nestor offs a name down
所以这基本上就是我
so that that's the basically what I
我想说的是第一和什么时候
wanted to say about number one and when
你已经看到了这个低谷你会看到的
you've seen this trough you'll see that
这是一个类似的想法涉及到
it's a similar idea of involving the
以前的时间值确定还有
previous time value ok there are very
现在用于机器的流行方法
popular methods in use now for machine
通过简单的学习来学习
learning that involves by a simple
通过以下方式计算所有先前的值
formula all the previous values by by
只是增加了一堆
sort of just by an addition of a bunch
条款所以它确实如此
of terms so it's really it
所以这就是ADAADA的名称
so it's it goes under the names ADA ADA
毕业或其他人已经
grad or others those of you who already
了解机器学习会知道
know about machine learning will know
我在说什么，我会说
what I'm speaking about and I'll say
更多关于那些是的，但事实并非如此
more about those yeah but it doesn't
每个都包含一个单独的系数
involve a separate coefficient for each
以前的价值或者是一个
previous value or that would be a
现在我做了大量的工作
momentous amount of work so so now I
只是想告诉你涅斯捷罗夫是什么
just want to tell you what Nesterov is
然后我们好OK先生。罗菲的
and then we were good ok mr. roffe's
想法让我把它带下来
idea let me bring that down
因为他有这个，所以把它打倒了
shoot this up bring down because he had
你可能没有想过的想法
an idea that you might not have thought
不知怎的，动量想法很漂亮
of somehow the momentum idea was pretty
自然地使用以前的值和
natural to use that previous value and
其实我想知道什么
actually I would like to know what
如果您使用两个先前的值，则会发生
happens if you use two previous values
或者你可以使用之前的三个值
or three previous values can you then
对此有所改进
get improvements on this this
回归两步收敛率
convergence rate by going back two steps
或者如果我使用类比的三个步骤
or three steps if I use the analogy with
常微分方程可能
ordinary differential equations maybe
你知道的就是这样，所以有
you know so right so so there are
后向差异公式你知道吗？
backward difference formulas do you know
关于这四个人的情况
about those four those would be in
MATLAB软件和所有其他软件
MATLAB software and all other software
落后的差异，所以也许你去
backward differences so maybe you go
如果你是的话，回来两步或四步
back two steps or four steps if you're
如果你正在进行行星计算
doing planetary calculations if you're
天文学家，你可能会回到七或
an astronomer you go back maybe seven or
八个步骤，以获得超高精度
eight steps to get super high accuracy
所以似乎没有发生过
so that doesn't seem to have happened
不过也应该发生在这里回去
yet but it should happen here to go back
更但却涅斯捷罗夫将具有它
more but but Nesterov will has it has
这种不同的回归方式让他如此
this different way to go back so his
公式是XK加一种新方法
formula is XK plus one the new way
是YK所以他正在介绍一些东西
is YK so he's introducing something a
有点不同-s辐射f@YK我是
little different - s radiant f @ YK I'm
对YK有点惊讶但是
a little surprised about that YK but
这是渐变的重点
this is the point here that the gradient
正在评估一些不同的
is being evaluated at some different
然后他必须给出一个公式
point and then he has to give a formula
那些跟踪那些明智的人
for that for those to track those wise
所以Y和X一样，但它们是
so the Y's are like the X's but they're
在一段时间内转移了一点点
shifted a little bit by some term and
测试就可以了哦，不行呀公测有
beta would be fine Oh No yeah beta have
我们得到了涅斯捷罗夫这里是老总掉了
we got Nesterov here yes mister off has
耶和华的因素，所以我没事
a factor gamma in yeah so I all right
让我让我尝试获得这项权利好吗
let me let me try to get this right okay
上一行我已经没事了
all right on the previous line I've
在这里写了整个巢穴的东西
written the whole nestdrop thing here
让我们完全看到漂亮的下降然后
let's see nice drop completely and then
他们会打破那么这是一步，
they'll break then this is the step that
把它分成两个第一顺序但是
breaks it into two first order but
你会在这里看到XKplus的主要公式
you'll see the main formula here XK plus
1是XK，然后β倍XK减去
1 is XK and then a beta times XK minus
XK减1，这就像一个动量
XK minus 1 so that's like a momentum
术语，然后是典型的梯度，但现在
term and then a typical gradient but now
这是Nesterov说出这个低谷
here's Nesterov speaking up this trough
评估梯度不是在XK而不是在
evaluates the gradient not at XK not at
XK减去1，但它是家里先生。奥兹点
XK minus 1 but it is home mr. Oz point
就像这样，这是Nesterov说我最喜欢的
like so this is Nesterov say my favorite
点伽玛XK减XK减1
point gamma XK minus XK minus 1 some
指向该步骤的一部分，所以它
point part way along that step so it so
这一点，因为伽玛将是
this point because gamma is going to be
一些非整数这个评价点
some non integer this evaluation point
对于F的梯度
of for the gradient of F
有点意外和奇怪，因为
is a little unexpected and weird because
它不是一个网格点，它在某个地方
it's not a mesh point it's somewhere
之间好吧是的，然后就是这样
between okay yep yep and then that so
涉及XK加1XK和XK减去
that involves XK plus 1 XK and XK minus
1所以这是一个二阶有一个
1 so it's a second-order there's a
我们要去的二阶方法
second-order method here we're going to
分析它我们将要去
it to analyze it we're going to go
通过与此相同写它的过程
through this same process of writing it
作为前两个的两个一阶步骤
as two first-order steps to first two
单步从k到k加一步
single step to one step from k to k plus
1所涉及的耦合一步法事情遵循
1 a a coupled one-step thing follow that
同样的事情，然后结果
same thing through and then the result
对他来说是一个相同的因素
is a same factor appears for him
同样的因素这也是如此
the same factor this is also so this the
点是这是动力和
point is this is for momentum and
涅斯捷罗夫与一些人
Nesterov with with some with some
常数差由一些不同的
constant difference different by some
不变但关键数量是
constant but the key quantity is that
一个和那个出现在两个所以我
one and that appears in both so so so I
当然不建议重复这些
don't propose of course to repeat these
酯的步骤，但你看到了什么
steps for an ester off but you see what
你看到你能做什么，你看到了
you see what you could do you see that
它涉及K减1Kink加1你
it involves K minus 1 K in k plus 1 you
当你按照一个特征向量写它
write it as you follow an eigen vector
你把它写成一个耦合系统
you write it as a coupled system of
这是一个有一个矩阵的一步
that's a one-step that has a matrix you
找到你找到特征的矩阵
find the matrix you find the eigen
你做的那些矩阵的值
values of the matrix you make those
特征值尽可能小，你
eigenvalues as small as possible and you
优化了它们的系数
have optimized their coefficients in
Nesterov确定那是那么多
Nesterov ok that's that's sort of a lot
代数的核心是
of algebra that's at the heart of
加速梯度下降和
accelerated gradient descent and of
当然值得做，因为它是一个
course it's worth doing because it's a
在中的巨大储蓄
tremendous saving in the in the in the
收敛率确定任何人都跑了
convergence rate ok anybody running in
马拉松或只是看着它
the marathon or just watching it's
无论如何我都会看到你可能知道
possible to run you know anyway I'll see
you after the marathon next Wednesday
你下周三马拉松之后
博伊德教授也会见到你
and professor Boyd will also see you